Post-type categories, their definitions, and examples


Non-abusive
Any content that does NOT contain insults, threats, ad hominem attacks, attacks on a person's identity (e.g., ethnicity, gender, sexual orientation, religion, 
political affiliation, immigration status, disabilities, etc...). Nor does the content indirectly promote harmful stereotypes or associates negative attribute to particular group of people (e.g., body shape, socioeconomic class, homelessness) or protected class (e.g., ethnicities, gender, sexual orientation, religion, disabilities).

Example:
"Perhaps they're not legitimate, civil comments."


Non-Abusive subclasses

Argumentative
Describes content that criticizes and/or is uncivil toward non-human entities and does NOT imply or indirectly allude to a human target. Non-human entities include articles/content, media outlets, public policies, works of art, food, or buildings/structures.

Example:
"On its face, Glueck's claim that AG Rosenblum needed a stronger settlement for her re-election is pretty silly. She currently has no opponent, and the Republicans have not fielded a primary candidate for AG in two election cycles."

Counter-speech
Content that is about abusive, hateful, or aggressive behavior and does NOT perform abuse targeting individuals. This includes any discussion that  identifies or defines abusive language, provides quoted examples of abusive language, or discussion facilitates discussion that opposes abusive language or behavior online. 

Example:
""Anybody who can kiss that many asses, that quickly, is so primed for success in the American workplace that they don't need your crappy restaurant job." ^This. Also, having been both the chatty person and the languishing-in-line-behind-the-chatty-person person, I think the best thing to do is smile and get over it.""

Casual profanity
Colloquial use of profanity that is not directed at any individual, such as, using profanity as an intensifier. 

Example
"Well shit, they drafted a guide. We should all be good now, whew aht a relief..."



Abusive
Content that contains hurtful language and includes hate speech, derogatory language (e.g., slurs, profanity directed at others, etc...)

Example:
"Liberals are just bone stupid. There can be no other rational explanation for their bias and ignorance."
"Ahh, these poor bleeding-heart liberal snowflakes....I think they should have these refugees (along with the usual assortment of terrorists) come live with them in their homes!"


Abusive Subclasses

Hate Speech
Instances that attacks or diminishes, incites/encourages violence or hate against individuals or groups based on being a part of a particular identity group such as: a person's country of origin, nationality/ethnicity/race, color, sex/sexual orientation/gender identity, or other protected class (derived from Fortuna & Nunes, 2018)

Example
"I'm going to call you as I see you regardless of what you want. You look like a man dressed as a woman it's going to be " hey man" and a woman dressed as a man is " hey ma'am". Not changing my ways for anybody, period. Feel free to call me whatever you like. I have thick skin and don't get butthurt over anything as dumb as pronouns. Don't like it, suck it up or don't converse with me. Saw a tranny the other day I could barely keep my composure without bursting out laughing let"

Offensive Language
Impolite language that "mocks" or "insults" an individual or group of people, but does not do so because of their membership in a particular identity group. This can include crude/squalid language, taboos, name calling, or hurtful language (Derived from Razavi et al., 2010)

Example:
"Another snowflake that can't handle reality. Funny how this snowflake didn't trow a fit when those same dogs were in the waiting area at the terminal and let's not forget all those cute hound dogs the TSA passes by with all over the airport sniffing around for illegal substances. I say lock her up in the animal cargo area on the next fight to help her deal with her imaginary cooties."

Explicit abuse
The use of language that demonstrates a deliberate on-record attack that explicitly causes social and/or psychological harm to those at whom it is directed. This includes the use of insults threats, ad hominem attacks, attacks on an individual's identity.

Example:
"This bitch is nuts." 

Implicit abuse
The use of veiled and indirect language that causes social and/or psychological harm to those at whom it is directed. This includes instances where a  comment/post alludes to stereotypes or other negative attributes and associates them with a particular group of individuals (e.g., body shape, socioeconomic class, homelessness).

Example:
"Will Whiteness History Month make all white people hate themselves? Will white students cry themselves to sleep for the rest of their lives?" Hahahahahaha. This makes me very happy. The whole idea sounds a little bit ridiculous but it's bound to spark some real political hostility! Hoorah for PCC." [L13]

"Who would read a book by a woman."


Outlier classes

Not enough information
Any content for which more context is needed to determine whether it is abusive or non-abusive.


